# Itamar Franco Salazar Reque

🔏 itamarsalazar.netlify.app | 🛅 itamarsalazar | 💆 @ItamarSalazar

## Summary\_

I am currently working in the group of Artificial Intelligence (AI) at INICTEL-UNI applying some machine learning and signal & image processing techniques to develop projects for national institutes in Peru. These projects are mostly related to agriculture and some biomedical applications. I did a remote internship at EPFL studying the inductive bias of Deep Neural Networks (DNN). I have teaching experience in signal processing and AI-related courses. During my master, I studied some techniques to solve the EEG inverse problem and in my undergrad I explored machine learning algorithms to automatically detect ill areas over plant leaves. My current interests are the applications of machine learning techniques and the study of their robustness.

## **Education**

### Universidad Nacional de Ingeniería

Lima, Perú

MASTER OF SCIENCE, ELECTRONIC ENGINEER

- Research on the performance of EEG inverse techniques when varying electrode numbers and noise.
- With scholarship from peruvian government

#### Universidad Nacional de Ingeniería

Lima, Perú

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE, TELECOMMUNICATION ENGINEERING

• Placed first in graduating class

## **Experience**

EPFL Lausanne, Switzerland

RESEARCH INTERN Oct. 2020 - March 2021

- · Studying the inductive bias of Deep Neural Networks under the direction of Pascal Frossard
- With scholarship from the peruvian government.

INICTEL-UNI Lima, Perú

SPECIALIZED RESEARCHER IN TECHNOLOGICAL DEVELOPMENT, COLLABORATOR

2018 - Present

- · We apply artificial intelligence and signal and image processing techniques to develop projects for national institutes in Peru:
- Avocado tree analysis using images acquired via drones. [Code ][About the project]
- Amplifying the small movements a person makes when breathing.[Code] [About the project]
- App to automatically identify avocado diseases from digital images. [About the project]
- Satellite image processing to calculate evapotranspiration. [About the project]]

#### Lecturer at different universities from Peru

Lima, Perú

03/2019 - Present

LECTURING IN:

DEVELOPER

- Signals and Systems Universidad Peruana de Ciencias Aplicadas (UPC): 04/2020-Present
- MLPs and introduction to Fuzzy Logic Universidad Tecnológica del Perú (UTP): 06/2019-03/2020
- Signals and Systems Universidad Nacional Tecnológica de Lima Sur (UNTELS): 03/2019 06/2019

NYIT New York, U.S.A

VISITING RESEARCH FELLOW

Oct. 2017 - Dec. 2017

• Studying CPA algorithm and methods to process functional imaging of olfactory bulb responses. This work was conducted by Dr. Gonzalo Otazu at NYIT.

PERU MENU Lima, Peru

• An app to find restaurants near to you.

07/2012 - 08/2012

• This was an informal job we made at university after winning a Hackaton, the job was directed by Federico Lara. Sadly the app never went to

#### Precursores de la Independencia Nacional (Secondary School)

*Lima, Peru* 07/2010 - 09/2010

TEACHING TO BEST STUDENTS

• I taught arithmetic to top-10 students from first secondary year. Precursores de la Independencia Nacional was my school and it was a tradition that old students teach to new ones. I am really proud of this work.

ITAMAR FRANCO SALAZAR REQUE · CV

## Contributions \_\_\_\_\_

	Ortiz-Jimenez, G., <b>Salazar-Reque, I.F.</b> , Apostolos Modas, Seyed-Mohsen Moosavi-Dezfooli, Pascal Frossard.	
[1]	A neural anisotropic view of underspecification in deep learning. In: Robust and Reliable Machine Learning	Workshop
	in the Real World Workshop at International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR 2021)	
[2]	<b>Salazar-Reque, I.F.</b> , Otazu G., Huaman S. (2020) Replacing FC layers in a CNN could improve robustness	Poster
[-]	against adversarial attacks. CIFAR DLRL Summer School (available under request)	, 55.61
	Salazar-Reque, I.F., Huaman, S. Automatic Leaf Segmentation from Images Taken Under Uncontrolled	- 6
[3]	Conditions Using Convolutional Neural Networks. In: Brazilian Technology Symposium'19 – Perú 2019	Conference
	(BTSym 2019), <b>DOI:</b> 10.1007/978-3-030-57566-3_27	
[4]	Morales, G., <b>Salazar-Reque, I.F.</b> , Telles, J., Díaz, D. Detecting Violent Robberies in CCTV Videos Using Deep	Conforma
[4]	Learning. In: 15th International Conference on Artificial Intelligence Applications and Innovations (AIAI 2019), <b>DOI:</b> 10.1007/978-3-030-19826-7	Conference
	Salazar-Reque, I.F., Pacheco, A.G., Rodriguez, R. Y., Lezama, J., and Huaman, S. An image processing	
[5]	method to automatically identify Avocado leaf state. In: XXII Symposium on Image, Signal Processing and	Conference
[-]	Artificial Vision (STSIVA 2019). <b>DOI:</b> 10.1109/STSIVA.2019.8730218	
	Salazar-Reque, I.F., Kemper G., Huamán S. G. H., Telles J. and Diaz D., (2019). An Algorithm for Plant Disease	
[6]	Visual Symptom Detection in Digital Images based on Superpixels. International Journal on Advanced	Journal
	Science, Engineering and Information Technology, 9(1), pp. 194-203, <b>DOI:</b> 10.18517/ijaseit.9.1.5322	
Ski <b>lls</b>		
	<b>Programming</b> Current: Python, MATLAB. Old: C++, Qt, Java, HTML	
Deep Le	arning Frameworks PyTorch, Keras, TensorFlow(learning)	
	<b>Languages</b> English (100/120 - TOEFL iBT), French (basic), Spanish (mother tongue)	
	Certifications Huawei Artificial Intelligence (HCIA-AI). [See certificate]	
	Miscellaneous Photography (Bird photography), Guitar	
Awar	ds	
2015	First place, undergraduate class	Lima, Perú
2017	Scholarship, fully funded master studies	Lima, Perú
2020	Scholarship, internship at EPFL	Lima, Perú
	· / · · · · · · · · · · · · · · · · · ·	,
Volur	iteering Activities	
2011 -	Active Volunteer, IEEE UNI Student Branch	Lima, Perú

# ٧

Active Volunteer, IEEE UNI Student Branch	Lima, Perú
Vice Chair, Circuits and Systems IEEE UNI Student Chapter	Lima, Perú
<b>Volunteer</b> , Rural Telecommunication Group	Lima, Perú
<b>Co-Founder</b> , Computer Science Research Group - GICS Dennis Ritchie	Lima, Perú
(https://es-la.facebook.com/GISCDennisRitchieUNI)	
Organizer, Student Congress - IEEE INTEERCON UNI 2011.	Lima, Perú
	Chair, IEEE UNI Student Branch, we publish some reports here: https://issuu.com/reieeeuni Vice Chair, Circuits and Systems IEEE UNI Student Chapter Volunteer, Rural Telecommunication Group Co-Founder, Computer Science Research Group - GICS Dennis Ritchie (https://es-la.facebook.com/GISCDennisRitchieUNI)